CARLOS GUTIERREZ DATA ANALYST

SUMMARY

Enthusiastic and conscientious Data Analyst and Machine Learning early career professional. Previously worked as non-profit organization general manager at Topstone Bibles & Books and Associate Program Director for The Church in Houston. Currently looking evaluate data using analytical, statistical and machine learning tools needed solve needs in industry.

SKILLS

SQL

Python

Inferential Statistics

Data Visualization (Matplotlib, Seaborn)

Pandas

Sci-kit learn

Flask

AWS EC2

AWS SageMaker

AWS RDS

AWS S3

CONTACT

Houston, TX 832-656-8468 chgutier@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/carlos-gutierrez-304267162



github.com/carlos-gutier



carlosgutier.com

EDUCATION

DATA ANALYSIS & MACHINE LEARNING

Lambda School | 2018 - 2019

Coursework: Linear Algebra, Hypothesis Testing and Inferential Statistics, Data Visualization and Communication, Advanced Regression, Model Validation, Data Engineering, Tree Ensembles, NLP, Neural Networks, Deep Learning.

BBA, FINANCE

University of Houston | 2002 - 2007

PROJECTS

INTERPRETING CUSTOMER CHURN WITH SURVIVAL ANALYSIS | 2019

- Used the Lifelines Python package to analyze data of customer tenure for a telecommunications company.
- Through survival analysis approach found statistically significant features that seemed to contribute to customer dropout.
- Recommended steps to take to increase customer retention based on findings.

RXID PILL IDENTIFIER APP | 2019

- Built baseline optical character recognition model using Tesseract and OpenCV to detect and read text imprint on prescription pills.
- Used AWS Rekognition, OpenCV image filter to read text from pill images and matched results with data in PostgreSQL database hosted on AWS RDS.

EMPLOYMENT

GENERAL MANAGER

Topstone Bibles & Books | Houston, TX | 2016 - 2018

- Oversee and coordinate with staff and volunteers for publication distribution in Southeast Texas venues and neighborhoods.
- Manage monthly educational events and yearly conferences.
- Oversee orders and customer satisfaction for online and retail bookstore.
- Hold bi-annual meetings with board of directors.

OUTREACH ASSOCIATE PROGRAM DIRECTOR

The Church in Houston | Houston, TX | 2009 - 2015

- Coordinate logistics and attendance for local and state conferences.
- Co-manage community outreach program for field recruitment and training.
- Lead area wide small groups to nurture members and develop their abilities to nurture fellow members.